<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Matthew Bunt</title>
        <link>https%3A//www.matthewbunt.org</link>
        <description>A blog about technology, life and being human</description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="https%3A//www.matthewbunt.org/tags/self/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Greetings, I&#x27;m Matt</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//www.matthewbunt.org/hello/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//www.matthewbunt.org/hello/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a 33 year old male who is fortunate enough to live in the beautifully temperate pacific northwest (USA). I am a technology enthusiast who enjoys all things &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Linux&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Open_source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. When it comes to opinionated ramblings about specific distributions of Linux, you&#x27;ll find I am almost exclusively a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;getfedora.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Fedora&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; user.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make a hobby out of studying computer programming. I am mostly using Rust these days, but in the past I&#x27;ve also used python. In school I learned about C#, Java and Perl, but I have not used those very much since then. Speaking of school, I have an associates degree in Data Networks and Telecommunications from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.clark.edu&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Clark College&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I almost completed a bachelors degree at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wgu.edu&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Western Governors University&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but personal and health problems have caused me to put that on hold for now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015 I began to have problems controlling my muscles. Unexplained pain soon turned into excessive weakness. In about an 8 month period I went from walking a mile to work everyday to barely being able to stand. From considering myself fairly strong, to feeling like a gallon of milk was more like a medicine ball. The doctors ran many blood tests, EEG&#x27;s and MRI&#x27;s. Every test came back &#x27;normal&#x27; but the symptoms remained. Finally after seeing my 4th neurologist I was told that I have &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Functional_neurological_symptom_disorder&quot;&gt;functional neurological disorder&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that brings me to the dervish dance that is my current emotional state. I have always battled with social anxiety, but after my diagnosis it grew worse and has been accompanied by depression. Thankfully I have great support from my family as well as a competent therapist.
Computer Video games has also always been a passion of mine. I love &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.blizzard.com&quot;&gt;Blizzard&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; games and am a huge fan of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;elderscrolls.bethesda.net&quot;&gt;Elder Scrolls&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; series. When I was younger I fancied myself a competitive StarCraft player, but since my muscles have stopped cooperating, I can&#x27;t really compete with other human players anymore. However, that is ok, I&#x27;ve gotten used to that fact and have embraced slower paced games like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;civilization.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Civilization&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that don&#x27;t require extreme speed or accuracy. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
